JEUEL VIVEROS

Dallas, TX 75218

Phone: 214 783-7757 | Email: vjeuel@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vjeuel | Github: https://github.com/vjeuel |

Portfolio: https://grafk.design/

SUMMARY

Graduated Full-Stack Web Developer at Southern Methodist University with a 4.0 GPA. Having owned a restaurant for over 17 years, acquired experience in public relations, finances, advertising, and training. While running a restaurant also freelanced as a Graphic Designer, designing advertising materials for various businesses. Known as a creative, is also adaptable, disciplined, and loves a challenge. Proficiency in HTML, CSS, React, jQuery, and studying across the full technical stack. Excited to keep learning and looking and forward to solving problems since I can think out of the box.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, HTML5, CSS3.

Other Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Spanish, and English

Applications: jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Heroku, Git, Handlebars.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Bootstrap Framework,

Materialize Framework, Material UI Framework, React, MERN Stack.

Transferable Skills: Flexible, Motivated, Organized, Avid learner, Yoga enthusiast, Seasonal cyclist, and

Troubleshooter

PROJECTS

CHIEF System | https://github.com/rgarza28/Inventory-Manager | https://lit-meadow-59526.herokuapp.com

- Inventory Management System, to help businesses to have a broad view of inventory at all times and alerts when a certain item is low in stock, decreasing the time of orders fulfillment by 50%.
- Teamed with 3 other students to write and develop this Inventory Management System.
- Led the execution of the Front End Development, User Interface, and User Experience Designs.
- Mobile responsive, developed with React, and used Material UI Framework, plus specific CSS3 styling.

Employee Directory | https://github.com/vjeuel/employee_directory | https://tinyurl.com/yxl92mfb

- Ability to search employees from the database, and also sort the table by name, phone number, and email.
- The columns contain 5 elements: employee photo, full name, phone number, email, and date of birth. Useful for companies to sort a long list of employees to find a specific person.
- Mobile responsive, built with React, pulling data from JSON, and styled with CSS3.

Fitness Tracker | https://github.com/vjeuel/Fitness_Tracker | https://tinyurl.com/y53rudyy

- Created to motivate users to be more active by tracking workouts, either cardio or weight lifting.
- This app uses asynchronous operations to get information from the database and post and update to add and make changes to entries in the database.
- Mobile responsive, implemented with HTML5, CSS3 using MongoDB for database, Node.js, and deployed on Heroku.

Budget Tracker | https://github.com/vjeuel/Budget-Tracker | https://tinyurl.com/y57azweq

• Set out to keep track of a budget, where the user can add and subtract funds, and the balance fluctuates accordingly.

 Mobile responsive, conceived with HTML5, CSS3 using MongoDB for database, Node.js, and deployed on Heroku.

Hungry at Home | https://github.com/vjeuel/food_api_app | https://vjeuel.github.io/food_api_app/

- For people who are at home in a Covid-19 lockdown, to give access to meals and drinks recipes and also to stay connected with news related to the virus.
- Partnered with 2 other students to work from the ground up on the development of this website.
- Created the design, using CSS3's Media Query in conjunction with the Materialize framework, and also facilitated the API's connections.
- Mobile responsive, written with HTML5, CSS3, Materialize Framework, CSS, and Javascript.

Restaurant Website | https://tinyurl.com/ychxobt3
Restaurant Website | https://github.com/vjeuel/carmines-pizzeria-grid | https://tinyurl.com/y9r7hthm

- 2 Restaurant's static websites are designed to present menus, specials, and contact information.
- Connected both sites to online ordering and had a sales boost of 25% and 32% in revenue respectively.

Weather | APP | https://github.com/vjeuel/weather app | https://vjeuel.github.io/weather app/

- A responsive website offers weather information and 5 days forecast, a particular feature is depending on the weather, the background changes accordingly to the weather condition.
- Mobile responsive and written using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and jQuery.

EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer | Freelancer | Dallas, TX | 02/2000 to Present

Data Processing Specialist | South Bend Specialty Pharmacy | South Bend, IN | 09/2019 to Present

Tony's Pizza and Pasta | Owner-Operator | Dallas, TX | 07/2003 to 07/2019

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate: 09/2020, GPA 4.0 | Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX. A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handlebars.js & React, MERN Stack.

College Education: Business Administration (2 years | incomplete) | UFMS, Campo Grande, MS, Brazil.

Advertising and Marketing (2 years | incomplete) | UCDB, Campo Grande, MS, Brazil.